Guide to the William A. Speck Collection of Goetheana: Medals and Medallions
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Medals and Reliefs Depicting Other People, 1740-1934; Series III; (30 items)
  - Ludwig Tieck/eagle with lyre, bronze medal. By Karl Reinhard Krüger., undated; 1 3/8 inches (Box 11, Folder 121)
    From envelope 58
  - Ludwig Uhland/text, bronze medal. By Adam Schiller. Centenary of his birth, 1887; 1 1/8 inches (Box 11, Folder 122)
    From envelope 130
  - Wilhelm von Weckbecker/text, medal. By Rudolph Ferdinand Marshall, 1934; 2 3/4 inches, rect. (Box 11, Folder 123)
    From envelope 132
  - Karl Friedrich Zelter/his coat of arms, copper medal. By Angelika Facius, 1831; 1 3/8 inches (Box 11, Folder 124)
    From envelope 56
- Larger Medallions and Reliefs, 1775-1924; Series IV; (19 items)
  - Goethe, in wooden mount, which is certainly much more recent than 1775. By Johann Peter Melchior, 9 1/4 x 7 inches, rect. (Box 11, Folder 125)
    L-0
  - Goethe, bronze plaque. By Leonhard Posch., [1827?]; 4 inches (Box 12, Folder 126)
    L-1
  - Goethe, bronze plaque. By Jean Pierre David d'Angers., 1829; 8 3/8 inches (Box 12, Folder 127)
    L-2
  - Goethe, verso: Weber Rosel & Co, Nürnberg N:6. By W. Passow, 1860; 7 3/4 inches (Box 12, Folder 128)
    L-3
  - Goethe, bronze plaque. By Gustav Kreß von Kressenstein. "Erinnerung an Goethe's Geburshaus" souvenir quality, 1863; 5 1/4 inches (Box 13, Folder 129)
    L-4
  - Goethe plaque. By Wincenty Trojanowski. Paris. With quotation from Faust, 1899; 10 x 7 3/4 inches, rect. (Box 13, Folder 130)
    L-5
  - Goethe, bronze plaque. By J. Rhein after J. K. Stieler., 1899; 3 3/4 inches (Box 13, Folder 131)
    L-6
  - Goethe/text. By Benno Elkan. Anniversaries of the Senckenbergische Naturforschende Gesellschaft, 1924; 5 3/8 inches (Box 13, Folder 132)
    L-7
  - Goethe. 20th century; screw holes along edge, undated; 12 x 9 1/4 inches, oval (Box 14, Folder 133)
    L-8
  - Goethe, two copies, different materials, undated; 7 1/2 x 6 inches, rect., 2 items (Box 15, Folder 134)
    L-9
  - Goethe and Schiller, two small rectangular reliefs (4.5 x 3.5 inches) mounted on a single wood block, undated; 11 1/2 x 8 inches, obl. (Box 16, Folder 135)
    L-10
  - Goethe and Schiller, two matching reliefs, souvenir quality, undated; 5 3/8 x 5/12 inches, 2 items (Box 17, Folder 136-137)
    L-11
  - Schiller, bronze plaque. By Jean Pierre David d'Angers. [Probably a set with L-2 above], [1829?]; 8 3/8 inches (Box 17, Folder 138)
    L-12
  - Schiller, laurel wreath colored gold, undated; 4 1/2 inches (Box 18, Folder 139)
    L-13
  - Schiller (?), in presentation box, undated; 3 5/8 inches (Box 18, Folder 140)
    L-14
  - Schiller, square relief, 2 1/4, mounted on wood, undated; 7 x 5 inches, rect. (Box 18, Folder 141)
    L-15
  - Wieland/text, coated iron? Presented on his 78th birthday, 1810; 3 5/8 inches (Box 18, Folder 142)
    L-16
- Similar Objects Made of Non-metallic Materials, 1932; Series V; (12 items)
  - Goethe, slate?, undated; 4 7/8 inches (Box 19, Folder 143)
    X-1
  - Goethe, slate? Chipped, lower left, undated; 4 1/4 inches (Box 19, Folder 144)
    X-2
  - Goethe, porcelain. By Metzler & Orloff, Ilmenau. Blue and white; issued by Goethe Nationalmuseum, Weimar, 1932; 3 1/2 inches (Box 19, Folder 145)
    X-3
  - Goethe/column & snake, Weimar, ceramic; 4 medallions showing stages of production. Meissen crossed swords. By Meissen (?), undated; 2 inches, 4 items in box (Box 19, Folder 146)
    X-4
  - Goethe/female figure, separate plaster casts of two sides of a medal, undated; 2 1/4 inches, 2 items (Box 19, Folder 147)
    X-5
  - Schiller, terracotta; gift of Faber du Faur; pencil inscription on back indicates that belonged to the family Cotta in Stuttgart. By Philipp Jakob Scheffauer., undated; 7 5/8 inches, oval (Box 20, Folder 148)
    X-6
  - Schiller, bois durci, undated; 4 1/2 inches (Box 20, Folder 149)
    X-7
  - Profile, porcelain; figure is possibly Johann Kaspar Lavater. By Meissen (?), undated; 3 1/4 inches (Box 20, Folder 150)
    X-8
  - [Described within Series I, II, and III, above] (Box 21, Folder 151-153)
- Original catalog cards, undated (Box 22)
  Arranged alphabetically by subject
- Original envelopes, undated (Box 23)
  Some include exhibit labels
  Arranged by envelope number